Guide to the Margaret K. Furbush collection of Janet Lewis material M2064
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Margaret K. Furbush collection of Janet Lewis material
unknown
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Furbush, Margaret M.
Brick Row Book Shop (San Francisco, Calif.)
M2064
11.26 Linear Feet 24 MSB, 2 Half boxes, 2 cassette boxes
Related Materials
There are other collections of Janet Lewis including ones containing media.
Biographical / Historical
Janet Lewis was an American novelist and poet, married to Yvor Winters, also an American poet and a literary critic. Janet also composed librettos. Margaret Furbush was a Stanford Library friend who worked in the Dept. of Special Collections, and was on the board of the Library Associates. She was the primary force behind the revival of the Library Associates’ journal, Imprint.
Scope and Contents
Materials consist of documents and media related to Janet Lewis and her writing, including correspondence, Lewis' manuscripts and correspondence related to them, and printed material.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase; 2015. Accession MSS 2015-032.
Furbush, Margaret M.; Brick Row Book Shop (San Francisco, Calif.); Lewis, Janet
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - Janet Lewis and Albert and Maclin Guerard, 1948-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother) 1 letter; Janet Lewis to parents with hand-written "The Manger" and with photograph of her plasticene sculpture, 1 letter, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 17 letters, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 40 letters, 1931-02-06-1931-09-22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 37 letters, 1931-09-16-1931-10-29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 29 letters, 1932-01-04-1932-03-31
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 45 letters, 1932-04-02-1932-06-13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 35 letters, 1932-08-23-1932-10-04 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 39 letters, 1932-10-05-1932-12-02 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 13 letters, 1932-12-03-1932-12-30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 38 letters, 1933-01-03-1933-03-03 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 12 letters, 1933-03-04-1933-03-27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 23 letters, 1933-04-24-1933-06-16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 34 letters, 1933-03-25-1933-05-16 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 8 letters, 1933-08-26-1933-09-22 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 60 letters, 1934-08-01-1934-11-27 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 33 letters, 1934-06-07-1934-07-30 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 41 letters, 1933-09-14-1933-11-14 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 30 letters, 1933-11-16-1933-12-30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 60 letters, 1934-01-03-1934-03-30 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Majority from Janet Lewis to Mrs. E. H. Lewis (mother), 40 letters, 1934-04-02-1934-06-04 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Janet Lewis and Charles Gullens, including typescript copy of The Swans, an opera in three acts, libretto by Janet Lewis, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Janet Lewis to various people (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - A (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
  - B (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Dorothy Baker (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - C (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Kathleen Campbell (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - D (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - D (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - John Daniel, publisher (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Donald and Doreen Davie (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - E (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - F (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - G (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Caroline Gordon (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Albert and Maclin Guerard (also see Box 1: 1-2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - H (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - I, J (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - K (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Kellock & Associates Ltd. (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - L (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Lewis Family (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - M (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
  - M (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - N (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - O (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - P (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - P (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Katherine Anne Porter (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
  - S (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - S (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
  - T (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - T (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - U, V (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - W (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - Kathryn Worth (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - X, Y, Z (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series 2. Manuscripts and Letters Relating to Them
  - A-C (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Awake My Love (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - About Elizabeth Madox Roberts (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Original and revised Elizabeth Madox Roberts, a Memoir (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Last of the Mohicans, libretto Janet Lewis (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - D-F (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Hildegarde Flanner (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - I Keep encountering her story.... (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Poems of Maurie Smith; Poems of Elizabeth Madox Roberts (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Notebook with diary, poems, notes (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - L-P (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Legend of Neengay (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Q-Y (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - When You Mee Greek (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - When Dorothy Baker died...; John Thow; Remember in the Pouring....; Yaddo, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous poems (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Proof sheets from a project volume of poems (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript fragments (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Re: TomoeTana translation of works, letters (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Yoshiko and the Porcelain Fox by Lucille M. Nixon and Janet Lewis, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Susan Lowell: Ganado Red (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Series 3. Other
  - 100th birthday celebration - in memorium (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Portrait of Janet Lewis; snapshots of house and grounds (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Worth, Kathryn: Signs of Capricornus, Alfred A. Knopf, N.Y.; Letter to Janet Lewis, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence including Janet and Margaret (Marmie) Furbush; Notes from visits with Janet starting Jine 11, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Ephemera (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
- Series 4. Booksellers, Catalogs, Lists, Bibliographies
  - Selected poems of Janet Lewis edited by Robert L. Barth (bookseller). Manuscript copy and correspondence of R. L Barth and M. Furbush, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence of R. L Barth and M. Furbush, 1990-1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Robert L. Barth bookseller, lists of Janet Lewis approximately 1992-1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence of M. Furbush with various booksellers (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Janet Lewis Collection of Margaret Furbush (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence relating to a bibliography of Janet Lewis' work (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Problems and questions relating to a bibliography of Janet Lewis' work (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Work of Janet Lewis 1980-1994, compiled 1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Materials prepared for Michael Ryan for his introduction to book on Janet Lewis' poetry with paintings by DeLoss McGraw July 21, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Janet Lewis' uncollecteds (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Janet Lewis letters JL:-AF1 in documents and on disk. A-D with additions (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Winters/Lewis personal library (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Elain Badgley project (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Janet Lewis' notes about introduction for Elaine Badgley catalogue (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - List of periodicals to which Janet Lewis contributed poems and copies of poems (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - Book reviews (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Series 5. Media: Audio-Visual and Cassettes
  - Janet Lewis as Lane Lecturer: 3 u-matic video cassette tapes and 1 VHS cassette tape dated November 5, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Nora and Janet: 5 u-matic video cassette tapes (Box 22)
  - Hildegarde, good comments by Janet reading - V. Land [?], 1 u-matic video cassette tape, number 1-4 (Box 22)
  - Janet reading, intro by Yvonne, and Janet reading at DeAnza College, 2 u-matic video cassette tapes marked as number 11 and 12 (Box 21)
  - Janet Lewis, her life a a writer, interview by Alva Henderson; Janet with Clive Wilmer and Helen Trimpi, 4 u-matic video cassettes with numbers of 1, 2, 4, 5 (Box 23)
  - Janet and Desiree [Desiree Doktor?] talking about moving into present house; photos excellent - 1 u-matic video cassette marked as number 9 (Box 23)
  - Janet Lewis 80th birthday celebration, 2 u-matic video cassettes, 1979-08 (Box 24)
  - Janet's birthday, 2 u-matic video cassettes [1989?] and 1 VHS videocassette dated 8-17-89 (Box 24)
  - Poets of the 40's: R. Duncan, R. Horan, R. Moore, J. Broughton, M. Gleason, J. Lewis, T. Parkinson, W. Everson - 1 VHS videocassette, 1974-04-04 (Box 24)
  - Tom Parkinson, 1 u-matic video cassette, marked as number 6, 1986-06-05 (Half-box 25)
  - Janet Lewis College of Creative Studies reading at UC Santa Barbara, 1 VHS videocassette, 1985-04-17 (Half-box 25)
  - Janet Lewis reading and conversation with Millicent Dillon, 1990-09-27 (Half-box 25)
  - Janet's birthday, 1 inch tape reel, Mold visible on outside of reel. (Half-box 26)
  - The Wife of Martin Guerre by William Bergsma, libretto by Janet Lewis, audio cassette, 1956-02-15 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis Reading at Stanford, audio cassette, 1975 (Box 27)
  - Dear Master by Dorothy Bryant, audio cassette, 1990-04-21 (Box 27)
  - The Ancient Ones, The Wonder of the World: words by Janet Lewis and music by Alva Henderson, audio cassette (Box 27)
  - Birthday of the Infanta: Janet Lewis libretto and Alva Henderson music, audio cassette, 1977-04-03 (Box 27)
  - El Encanto: Janet Lewis and Jeff Akard, Santa Barbara, audio cassette, 1987-07-07 (Box 27)
  - Jeff Akard, Janet Lewis' bibliography, Santa Barbara, audio cassette, 1987-07-07 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis, questions at lunch, audio cassette, 1988-10-05 (Box 27)
  - The Strength of Art, Winters/Lewis; Henry Ramsey, Edgar Bowers, ASUL Lecture, audio cassettes 1-2, 1984-03-11 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis Winters: [Crow?], audio cassette, 1979-02-07 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis with Dorothy Bryant KPFA, audio cassette, 1987-11-24 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis Winters birthday party, 2 audio cassettes, 1980-04 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis at Booktasters, audio cassette, 1986-02-27 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis looking for copies of The Wife of Martin Guerre in Janet's living room, audio cassette, 1988-07-26 (Box 27)
  - Janet Lewis Laffont Letters, audio cassette, 1988-05 (Box 27)
  - The Legend: Janet Lewis libretto, Bain Murray music, 2 audio cassettes (Box 28)
  - Third Ingredient (title for Mulberry Street), opera, San Jose, fall 1988 - study tape; with The Room Across the Hall now incorporate into West of Washington Square, 7-26-88, audio cassette (Box 28)
  - Mulberry Street, 1988, Alva Henderson, libretto Janet Lewis, audio cassette (Box 28)
  - Catherine Parke interviewing Janet Lewis, audio cassette, 1989-02-17 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis on William Saroyan, audio cassette, 1996-07-30 (Box 28)
  - Three Songs by Alva Hemnderson; Three poems by Janet Lewis, set to music by Alva Henderson, audio cassette (Box 28)
  - Eva Christmas 1983, audio cassette (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis at Califia reading from Janet and DeLoss and in conversation with Millicent Dillon, audio cassette, 1989-09-27 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, includes happy 90th birthday wishes, microcassette, 1989-03-30 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis trip to the Sault (?) for reunion (bicentennial), microcassette, 1992-07-16 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, Sunmount and Santa Fe; The Wife and The Return of Martin Guerre, microcassette, 1993-02-10 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, microcassette, 1993-02-25 and 1993-04-02 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, 4 microcassettes: April 2, 1993 and August 3, 1993; July 24-26, 1993 (Aunt Eva); March 17, 1994 and April 28, 1994; April 28, 1994 and Mau 5, 1994 (some over-record on May 16, 1994), 1994 tapes twisted in one spot (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis on Tagore and on unfinished manuscript, microcassette, 1994-07-18 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, 2 microcassettes, December 5, 1997 and April 3, 1998; August 1997 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, Santa Fe, Hart Crane, Katherine Ana Porter - letter writing, microcassette, 1998-09-25 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, Achilles Holt, microcassette, 1998-04-10 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, identification of letters, Esther ?, Sunmount, microcassette, 1998-04-10 (Box 28)
  - Janet Lewis, Early days - summers in Rhode Island, Ben Franklin, Neebish, new edition of The Invasion, microcassette, 1998-10-22 (Box 28)